RONNY TORIBIO BLANCO

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

▼ronnytoribio1@hotmail.com
\$\square\$ 3475599604

SUMMARY

I am a FullStack Web Developer, with a passion to learn new and exciting programs and utilize them in my day-to-day coding. I have experience building applications with Ruby on Rails, Python Flask, and JavaScript, as well as React and Redux. I am comfortable working in a FullStack environment and can easily transition from coding in the Back End to the Front End with ease.

When not trying to create the next best Website, I'm usually working on cars, playing basketball, or improving on my photography!

SKILLS

JavaScript, reactJs, react-native, ruby, ruby on rails, redux, sql, Active record, HTML, CSS, SASS, Sinatra, Python3, Bootstrap, flask, SQL Alchemy, Peewee, Selenium, Py Game, TKinter, nodeJs, expressJs, Sequalize, figma

EMPLOYMENT

Transparent Language

Software QA · Jan. 2019 to Current · Nashua, New Hampshire

Was part of an Agile testing team, that manually tested user interface on both mobile and desktop respectively. Trained new team members that were going to join the QA team or "bench" as we called it Was in charge of notification API testing

Getinge

Stager · Mar. 2018 to Dec. 2018 · Merrimack

Increased workflow and productivity by retrieving essential parts for line employees.

Target

Sales Associate · Apr. 2017 to Sept. 2017 · Nashua, New Hampshire

Applied my bilingual communication skills to increase customer satisfaction and to assist them when needed.

PROJECTS

Virtual Menu

This is a simple web app that's written in react.js with a rails backend that shows has a virtual menu for restaurants which is easier to read and is better than the pdf most restaurants use

Raffle Dazzle

A simple web app, written in ruby on rails where users are able to raffle items and join raffles too, it also allows users to be able to control when to start the raffle and when to end it as well.

Home Password

This is a simple web app using a python flask backend that allows users to store and share a site and their passwords.

Py Pong

This is a simple pong game made with the python Pygame module

EDUCATION

Flatiron School · Sept. 2020 to July 2021

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails, and JavaScript programming Bootcamp